- 让我们研究如何为词元分类
- Let's study how to preprocess a dataset
预处理数据集！
for token classification!
任何对于单词进行标记
Token classification regroups any task
或者对词元进行标记的任务
that can be framed as labeling each word
均可以由词元分类进行重新组合，
or token in a sentence,
比如识别人物、组织
like identifying the persons, organizations
和位置之类。
and locations for instance.
对于本例来说，我们将使用 Conll 数据集，
For our example, we will use the Conll dataset,
在其中我们删除了我们不会使用的列
in which we remove columns we won't use
并重命名其他的以获取数据集
and rename the other ones to get to a dataset
其中只有两列，即 words 和 labels。
with just two columns, words and labels.
如果你有自己的词元分类数据集，
If you have your own dataset for token classification,
请确保你清理数据以达到相同的效果，
just make sure you clean your data to get to the same point,
包括 words 列内含字符列表
with one column containing words as list of strings
和另一个 labels 列内含整数
and another containing labels as integers
从零到你的标签数量减一。
spanning from zero to your number of labels minus one.
确保将标签名称存储在某处。
Make sure you have your label names stored somewhere.
在这里，我们从数据集特征中获取它们。
Here we get them from the dataset features.
所以你检查数据时
So you are able to map the integers to some real labels
可以将整数映射到一些真实的标签。
when inspecting your data.
这里我们正在做命名实体识别，
Here we are doing named entity recognitions,
所以对于不属于任何实体的词
so ours labels are either O
我们的标签可能是 O 。
for words that do not belong to any entity.
LOC 代表位置，PER 代表个人，ORG 代表组织
LOC for location, PER for person, ORG for organization
和 MISC 杂项。
and MISC for miscellaneous.
每个标签有两个版本。
Each label has two versions.
B 标签表示以实体开始的单词
The B labels indicate a word that begins an entity
而 I 标签表示实体内部的单词。
while the I labels indicate a word that is inside an entity.
预处理我们数据的第一步
The first step to preprocess our data
是将单词词元化。
is to tokenize the words.
使用分词器很容易做到这一点。
This is very easily done with the tokenizer.
我们只需要告诉它我们已经预先词元化了数据
We just have to tell it we have pre-tokenized the data
带有标志 is_split_into_words=True。
with the flag is_split_into_words=True.
然后是困难的部分。
Then comes the hard part.
由于我们添加了特殊词元
Since we have added special tokens
每个单词可能被拆分成几个词元，
and each word may have been split into several tokens,
我们的标签将不再与词元匹配。
our labels won't match the tokens anymore.
这是我们的快速分词器提供的单词 ID
This is where the word IDs our fast tokenizer provides
前来救援。
come to the rescue.
他们将每个词元与其所属的单词匹配
They match each token to the word it belongs to
这允许我们将每个词元映射到它的标签。
which allows us to map each token to its label.
我们只需要确保
We just have to make sure
我们针对里面的词元将 B 标签
we change the B labels to their I counterparts
更改为对应的 I
for tokens that are inside
但不是在单词的开头。
but not at the beginning of a word.
特殊词元的标签为 -100，
The special tokens get a label of -100,
这就是当计算损失时我们告诉 Transformer 损失函数
which is how we tell the Transformer loss functions
要忽略它们。
to ignore them when computing the loss.
然后代码非常简单明了。
The code is then pretty straightforward.
我们针对可以自定义的单词内的词元
We write a function that shifts the labels
写了一个函数来移动标签
for tokens that are inside a word that you can customize
并在为每个词元生成标签时调用它。
and use it when generating the labels for each token.
一旦编写了创建标签的函数，
Once that function to create our labels is written,
我们可以使用 map 函数预处理整个数据集。
we can preprocess the whole dataset using the map function.
使用选项 batched=True，
With the option batched=True,
我们释放了快速分词器的速度。
we unleash the speed of out fast tokenizers.
当我们需要创建一个批处理任务时，最后一个问题就来了。
The last problem comes when we need to create a batch.
除非你改变了预处理函数
Unless you changed the preprocessing function
增加一些固定的填充，
to apply some fixed padding,
否则我们会得到各种长度的句子，
we will get sentences of various lengths,
我们需要将其填充到相同的长度。
which we need to pad to the same length.
填充处理需要在输入
The padding needs to be applied to the inputs
以及标签上进行，
as well as the labels,
因为每个词元应该有一个标签。
since we should have one label per token.
同样，-100 表示应忽略的标签
Again, -100 indicates the labels that should be ignored
用于损失计算。
for the loss computation.
所有这一切
This is all done for us
都通过 DataCollatorForTokenClassification 为我们完成了，
by the DataCollatorForTokenClassification,
你可以在 PyTorch 或 TensorFlow 中使用它。
which you can use in PyTorch or TensorFlow.
完成上述内容后，你就可以准备发送数据了
With all of this, you are either ready to send your data
并将此数据整理器传递给 Trainer，
and this data collator to the Trainer,
或者使用 to_tf_dataset 方法
or use the to_tf_dataset method
以及模型的拟合方法。
and the fit method of your model.